"use strict";(self.webpackChunkquiz_app=self.webpackChunkquiz_app||[]).push([[658],{658:e=>{e.exports=JSON.parse('[{"question":"What is AWS Route 53?","answers":[{"text":"A content delivery network service","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A domain name registration service","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A managed DNS service","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A serverless compute service","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which record type in Route 53 is used to map a domain name to an IPv4 address?","answers":[{"text":"CNAME","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A","isCorrect":true},{"text":"MX","isCorrect":false},{"text":"PTR","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the primary purpose of a hosted zone in Route 53?","answers":[{"text":"To store backup copies of your website","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To manage SSL certificates for your domains","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To store information about how to route traffic for a domain","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To store data for your relational databases","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the TTL (Time to Live) in Route 53 used for?","answers":[{"text":"To specify the transfer time for DNS records","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To determine the maximum age of DNS responses in cache","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To set the expiration time for SSL certificates","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To configure the routing policies for traffic","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a Traffic Policy in Route 53 used for?","answers":[{"text":"To manage traffic signals at intersections","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To define how Route 53 responds to DNS queries based on geographic locations","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To configure SSL/TLS settings for a domain","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To control the flow of data between databases","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which routing policy in Route 53 is used to route traffic to multiple resources in a weighted distribution?","answers":[{"text":"Latency-based routing","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Simple routing","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Geolocation routing","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Weighted routing","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is a Health Check in Route 53 used for?","answers":[{"text":"To monitor the CPU utilization of instances","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To monitor the status of resources and endpoints","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To track the number of requests to a website","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To monitor the latency of network connections","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which record type is used to redirect a domain name to another domain in Route 53?","answers":[{"text":"A","isCorrect":false},{"text":"CNAME","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Alias","isCorrect":true},{"text":"MX","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of the Alias record type in Route 53?","answers":[{"text":"To create a virtual IP address for routing traffic","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To specify the mail server for the domain","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To define the authoritative DNS server for the domain","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To configure the reverse DNS lookup for the domain","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which AWS service can be integrated with Route 53 for registering and managing domain names?","answers":[{"text":"Amazon S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"AWS Lambda","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon Route 53 Domain Registration","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Amazon RDS","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of the AWS Route 53 Resolver?","answers":[{"text":"To optimize the delivery of content through caching","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To resolve DNS queries for resources in an Amazon VPC","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To manage SSL certificates for domains","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To route traffic based on geographic locations","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the maximum number of domain names that can be associated with a single hosted zone in Route 53?","answers":[{"text":"1","isCorrect":false},{"text":"10","isCorrect":false},{"text":"50","isCorrect":false},{"text":"100","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which DNS record type is used to specify mail servers for the domain?","answers":[{"text":"CNAME","isCorrect":false},{"text":"MX","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A","isCorrect":false},{"text":"PTR","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of the Amazon Route 53 Auto Naming service?","answers":[{"text":"To automatically register IP addresses for instances in a VPC","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To automatically assign domain names to EC2 instances based on their tags","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To automatically discover and register AWS resources","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To automatically configure routing policies for domains","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of the Amazon Route 53 Resolver Endpoint?","answers":[{"text":"To configure health checks for Route 53 endpoints","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To resolve DNS queries between on-premises networks and AWS","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To manage routing policies for domain names","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To enable cross-region replication of DNS records","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which routing policy in Route 53 is used to route traffic to the endpoint that has the lowest latency?","answers":[{"text":"Simple routing","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Weighted routing","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Latency-based routing","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Geolocation routing","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of the Amazon Route 53 Resolver Rule?","answers":[{"text":"To configure routing policies for domain names","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To define how Route 53 responds to DNS queries based on geographic locations","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To specify custom domain names for AWS resources","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To forward DNS queries from one VPC to another","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which AWS service can be integrated with Route 53 to distribute content globally through a content delivery network?","answers":[{"text":"Amazon RDS","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon CloudFront","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Amazon S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"AWS Elastic Beanstalk","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of the Routing Policy \'Failover\' in Route 53?","answers":[{"text":"To route traffic to the endpoint with the lowest latency","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To route traffic based on the geographical location of the user","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To route traffic to a backup endpoint when the primary is unhealthy","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To route traffic to multiple endpoints in a weighted distribution","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which AWS service provides a scalable and highly available authoritative DNS service?","answers":[{"text":"Amazon Route 53","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Amazon S3","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon CloudFront","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Amazon Elastic Block Store (EBS)","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of the Amazon Route 53 Resolver Query Log?","answers":[{"text":"To store logs of DNS queries for troubleshooting purposes","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To track the performance of Amazon Route 53 endpoints","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To monitor the CPU utilization of DNS servers","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To configure routing policies for domain names","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the purpose of the \'www\' record in Route 53?","answers":[{"text":"To specify mail servers for the domain","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To configure routing policies for domain names","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To define the authoritative DNS server for the domain","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To create an alias for the domain or a subdomain","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"How does Route 53 support domain name registration?","answers":[{"text":"By providing SSL/TLS certificates","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By enabling cross-region replication of DNS records","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By integrating with the Amazon Route 53 Domain Registration service","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By configuring health checks for domains","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which DNS record type is used to map a domain name to an alias?","answers":[{"text":"A","isCorrect":true},{"text":"CNAME","isCorrect":false},{"text":"MX","isCorrect":false},{"text":"PTR","isCorrect":false}]}]')}}]);